ukcdogs.com 2019-05-12

# Privacy | United Kennel Club (UKC)

Protecting your personal information is important to United Kennell Club (UKC), 100 E. Kilgore Road, Kalamazoo, MI 49002, USA ("United Kennel Club","UKC" or "we", "us", "our"). Please note that UKC is located outside of the European Union, in the United States, and thus in addition to the General Data Protection Regulation (whenever applicable), U.S. law may apply to certain aspects of having your data collected and processed. 

At UKC we take your privacy seriously and understand your concerns regarding the right to control your personal information submitted through the UKC website. This privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") will explain what type of information we may collect from you or that you may provide when you visit the website URL(s) at [www.ukcdogs.com](https://www.ukcdogs.com/ "UKC website") ("website"), our practices for collecting, using, maintaining, protecting, disclosing that information, how users can access information that they submit through the website, and whom information may be shared with. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect on our website, web pages, interactive features, applications and blogs, relating to services we offer, and their respective contents, whether accessed via computer, mobile device, or other technology (collectively, the "Sites"). 

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and review it on a regular basis. 

## The Type of Information We Collect

### Information You Provide to Us

Based on the consent granted (provided that no other circumstance when processing Personal Information without consent legally applies), we collect information that you have provided to contact you or to identify you personally, such as your name, company name, email address, postal address, phone number, or any other information that identifies you ("Personal Information"). We also collect aggregate information (such as how users access the website). As is true with most websites, we gather web server log file information automatically, such as your browser type, IP address, referring/exit page, and operating system. 

If you choose to use the Contact Us form on the website, you will be asked for general information, including name, company, city, phone and email address. UKC will use this information to better understand who you are and to identify the best person to contact you from within UKC. UKC stores this information for at least one year. 

Provided that you grant consent, you may also submit your resume via email. This information will be reviewed by our Human Resource department for recruitment purposes only. If positions are not available at the time of submission, UKC will store your resume for at least one year so that we may review it for future opportunities. Your Personal Information gathered for the purpose of recruitment will not be shared or transferred to any other third party. 

UKC will never knowingly collect information from children. For consent to be valid, it must be granted by an individual of 16-years old or older. By consenting to this policy, you declare you are 16 years or older. If, despite the language of the consent, it is found that information is collected from a child below the age of 16, that user would be notified that his or her Personal Information cannot be accepted, and that Personal Information would be removed from our records immediately. 

## How We Use Personal Data

We use your Personal Information to provide marketing services, not to mine or sell your data. 

We use your Personal Information to provide services to you and to communicate with you by email, track visitor utilization of the site, and market our services. 

We use cookies to track website activity, identify unique visitors to UKC and provide a positive user experience. 

## Reasons We Share Personal Data

Personal Information we gather is for internal use only and we will not authorize the release of this information to anyone outside UKC, except as clearly described below. 

We may release information we collect to authorized third parties so they can perform functions on our behalf and on behalf of you, our customer. These third parties have agreed to use at least the same level of privacy protections described in this Privacy Policy and are permitted to use the information only for the purpose of performing these functions. 

Should you breach our Terms of Service, or if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligations, we may disclose your information to a relevant authority. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for the purposes of fraud protection and risk reduction. Specifically, we may release the information we collect to third parties when we believe it is appropriate to comply with the law, to enforce our legal rights, to protect the rights and safety of others, or to assist with industry efforts to control fraud, spam or other undesirable conduct. 

## How Long Do We Store Your Data

  * UKC will keep contact form data for at least one year. 
  * UKC will keep applications for job postings for at least one year so that we may review it for future opportunities. Your Personal Information gathered for the purpose of recruitment will not be shared or transferred to any other third party. 

## Authorized Third Parties

### Email Providers

  * Mailchimp - UKC uses Mailchimp to send emails. Mailchimp only uses the information we share with them to send these emails. Mailchimp adheres to the [Mailchimp Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/ "Mailchimp Privacy Policy"). 

### Tools

  * Google Analytics - UKC uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies to help analyze how individuals use websites they visit. Non-personal information generated by this cookie about your use of UKC's website is transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google does not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Google uses this information to understand how you use UKC's website, and compiles reports on this activity to help us improve our site for our users. By using UKC's website, you consent to the processing of data about you by [Google](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=us "Google Privacy Policy") for these purposes. You may disable cookies within your browser to block this tracking by Google, understanding that doing so may affect your ability to use the full functionality of our site. For certain browsers, you can also prevent Google from collecting information (including your IP address) via cookies and processing this information by downloading and installing this [browser plug-in](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Browser plug-in"). 

## How to Request Access, Update, Rectification, Erasure, and Restriction of Processing of Personal Information

To access, review, update, amend, erase, or restrict processing of Personal Information, please email us or call (269) 343-9020. You may opt out of future contact via the same method. 

UKC will take commercially reasonable efforts to provide you with an accounting of the Personal Information we may have within a reasonable period of time. If we are unable to process your request, you will be provided with an explanation. 

## Security

At UKC the security of the Personal Information that you submit via our website is our priority. We use reasonable administrative, technical, and physical safeguards to protect your information from loss, unauthorized access, unauthorized destruction, use, modification, or disclosure of information and require the same controls from our affiliates. 

You may contact UKC at any time by emailing us or call (269) 343-9020 to request access to your Personal Information, to have it rectified, erased, and/or to restrict its processing. You may also request to have your Personal Information provided to you in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format, as well as to have it transmitted to another entity at your request. 

## Changes to This Policy

We reserve the right to change this notice at any time. We will post a notice of the effective date of changes to the Policy on our website. 

## Right to Lodge a Complaint

If you feel that UKC does not comply with this policy or violates the law, you are entitled to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority in the Country/EU Member State where you reside. 

Updated January 2, 2019
